export const INFORMATIONCOMMUNICATIONTECHA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "The first calculator was built by?",
A: "Marie Jacquad",
B: "Balise Pascal",
C: "Charles Babbage",
D: "John Napier",
answer: "B. Balise Pascal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "A similarity between data and information is that both?",
A: "can be displayed on the monitor",
B: "are computer inputs",
C: "are processed facts",
D: "are computer results",
answer: "A. can be displayed on the monitor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "The computer hardware can be classified into",
A: "ALU and Control Unit",
B: "System Unit and Peripheral",
C: "Central Processing Unit and Control Unit",
D: "Input and Output Units",
answer: "B. System Unit and Peripheral",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "The outcome of a processed data in a computer is known as",
A: "raw fact",
B: "Information",
C: "database",
D: "computer result",
answer: "D. computer result",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "Which of the following devices is not a micro-computer?",
A: "Note book",
B: "Laptop",
C: "EDVAC",
D: "Desktop",
answer: "C. EDVAC",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "Which of the following computing devices did not exist in the pre-computing age to the 19th century?",
A: "Napier's bone",
B: "Abacus",
C: "ENIAC",
D: "Slide Rule",
answer: "C. ENIAC",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "The computing devices invented by Charles Babbage are?",
A: "Difference Engine and Abacus",
B: "Analytical Engine and Slide Rule",
C: "Abacus and Slide Rule",
D: "Analytical and Difference Engines",
answer: "D. Analytical and Difference Engines",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "In a computer, the sets of instruction that direct it in performing a particular task is called?",
A: "information",
B: "program",
C: "data",
D: "file",
answer: "B. program",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "The property of a disk that determines the amount of data it may contain is?",
A: "size",
B: "volume",
C: "storage capacity",
D: "storage power",
answer: "C. storage capacity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "Which of the following items best describes the term hardcopy?",
A: "Print out",
B: "Written on a hardboard",
C: "Information stored on a hard disk",
D: "Amount of data",
answer: "A. Print out",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "Which of the following is not an output device?",
A: "Plotters",
B: "Speakers",
C: "Projectors",
D: "Webcams",
answer: "D. Webcams",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "Which of the following signifies the correct association between a hardware component and its functions?",
A: "Mouse to input",
B: "Monitor to print",
C: "CPU to storage",
D: "Hard disk to processing",
answer: "A. Mouse to input",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "Fig 1 represents_________?",
A: "an AND gate",
B: "an OR gate",
C: "a NOT gate",
D: "a NAND gate",
answer: "B. an OR gate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "In Fig. 1, X, Y, and Z respectively represent_______?",
A: "Input, Output and Input signals",
B: "Output, Output and Input signals",
C: "Output, Input and Output Signals",
D: "Input, Input and Output signals",
answer: "D. Input, Input and Output signals",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "Which of the following software is best suitable for keeping records during national population census?",
A: "Word Processing",
B: "Spreadsheet",
C: "Graphic",
D: "Database",
answer: "D. Database",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "A major function of system software is_________?",
A: "Collection of Files",
B: "Translation of machine language into machine code",
C: "File management",
D: "Arrangement of files in ascending order",
answer: "C. File management",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "An advantage of Graphical User Interface (GUI) over Disk Operating System (DOS) is that it allows the use of __________?",
A: "Diskette",
B: "Keyboard",
C: "Mouse",
D: "Monitor",
answer: "C. Mouse",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "Which of the following methods is not suitable for securing files?",
A: "Use of backup",
B: "Use of antivirus",
C: "Saving documents without a password",
D: "Proper labelling of storage devices",
answer: "C. Saving documents without a password",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "Which of the following programming languages needs no translator for it to run?",
A: "High-Level Language",
B: "Low Level Language",
C: "Machine Language",
D: "Assembly Language",
answer: "C. Machine Language",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "The path labelled I is the __________?",
A: "System design",
B: "System implementation",
C: "Study review",
D: "Feasibility study",
answer: "D. Feasibility study",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "The path labelled II is the __________?",
A: "System design",
B: "System implementation",
C: "Study review",
D: "Feasibility study",
answer: "A. System design",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "The path labelled III is the _________?",
A: "System design",
B: "System implementation",
C: "Study review",
D: "Feasibility study",
answer: "C. Study review",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "The part labelled I represents_________",
A: "Begin/Start Symbol",
B: "Process/Action Symbol",
C: "Read/Write Symbol",
D: "Stop/End Symbol",
answer: "C. Read/Write Symbol",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "The part labelled II represents______",
A: "Decision Symbol",
B: "Read/Write Symbol",
C: "Process Symbol",
D: "Stop/End Symbol",
answer: "C. Process Symbol",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "The part labelled III represents________",
A: "Process/Action Symbol",
B: "Decision Symbol",
C: "Read/Write Symbol",
D: "Stop Symbol",
answer: "B. Decision Symbol",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "The acronym HTTP stands for________",
A: "Hyper Text Transfer Protocol",
B: "Higher Transfer Text Protocol",
C: "Hard Text Transfer Protocol",
D: "Higher Text Transfer Protocol",
answer: "A. Hyper Text Transfer Protocol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "In ring topology, the computer that is allowed to transmit data possesses the ________",
A: "Packet",
B: "Data",
C: "Access method",
D: "Token",
answer: "D. Token",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "The most cost-effective and secure way of transmitting confidential messages among the employees of an organization is the ___________",
A: "Electronic notice boards",
B: "Teleconferencing",
C: "E-mail",
D: "Social networks",
answer: "C. E-mail",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "The application software which allows information available on the internet to be obtained is called _________",
A: "Browser",
B: "World Wide Web",
C: "Spreadsheet",
D: "Internet Protocol",
answer: "A. Browser",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "A modern and a telephone connection are provided. Other things needed to be able to connect a computer to the internet are _______",
A: "ISP account and Utility software",
B: "Browser and ISP account",
C: "ISP account and Network",
D: "Browser and Printer",
answer: "C. ISP account and Network",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "Which of the following is employed in the transfer of data between computers and a network?",
A: "Fiber optics",
B: "Male connector",
C: "Female Connector",
D: "USB Port",
answer: "D. USB Port",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "Which of the following software can be used for graphic production?",
A: "DOS Editor",
B: "PC Writer",
C: "Coreldraw",
D: "Acrobat Reader",
answer: "C. Coreldraw",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "In word processing, the icon in Fig.4 is used for __________",
A: "Paging",
B: "Line Spacing",
C: "Numbering",
D: "Bulleting",
answer: "C. Numbering",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "Which of the following items is not located on the MS Word menu bar?",
A: "Home",
B: "Open",
C: "View",
D: "Mailings",
answer: "B. Open",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "In table 3, the content of cell C5________",
A: "2456",
B: "4009",
C: "4400",
D: "3450",
answer: "B. 4009",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "The number of cells that contain data in row 1 is_________",
A: "1",
B: "3",
C: "5",
D: "7",
answer: "C. 5",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "Which cells in table 3 contain numeric data with the least value?",
A: "A5",
B: "B5",
C: "C5",
D: "D5",
answer: "B. B5",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "In changing the storage location of a file, the command to use is_______",
A: "ctrl + S keys",
B: "'save' command",
C: "'save as' command",
D: "alt + F, then save",
answer: "C. 'save as' command",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "Which of the following statements is true about registers?",
A: "It is storage area around CPU",
B: "It is situated beside the CPU",
C: "It is situated beside the memory",
D: "It is a special high speed storage area within the CPU",
answer: "D. It is a special high speed storage area within the CPU",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "The Instruction fetched into the CPU is decoded by the___________",
A: "Primary memory",
B: "Program counter",
C: "ALU",
D: "Control unit",
answer: "D. Control unit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "The process of restarting a computer is known as ________",
A: "Cold booting",
B: "Warm booting",
C: "Resume booting",
D: "Restart booting",
answer: "B. Warm booting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "Evaluate the BASIC statement: LET Z = 4*W^2  + 2*Y Given that W = 5 and Y = 10",
A: "50",
B: "80",
C: "100",
D: "120",
answer: "D. 120",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "Given that 26 10 = X 2, X is _________",
A: "11011",
B: "11010",
C: "11110",
D: "10111",
answer: "B. 11010",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "In hexadecimal number system, B, D, E represent_________",
A: "11, 12, 13 respectively",
B: "12, 14, 15 respectively",
C: "13, 14, 15 respectively",
D: "14, 16, 17 respectively",
answer: "B. 12, 14, 15 respectively",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "The conversion of 11001 2 to base 10 equals_______",
A: "30",
B: "28",
C: "25",
D: "20",
answer: "C. 25",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "The transaction file can also be described as _______",
A: "Master File",
B: "Movement file",
C: "Reference file",
D: "Historical file",
answer: "B. Movement file",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "Which of the following statements is not true about a computer file?",
A: "It is very fast to access any record within a file",
B: "It is created electronically",
C: "Initial setup is inexpensive",
D: "File creation and access are less laborious",
answer: "C. Initial setup is inexpensive",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "An advantage of sequential access over serial access is that_______",
A: "Sequential file is slow",
B: "Sequential file is detailed",
C: "Sequential file does not use key",
D: "Individual records can be located more quickly",
answer: "B. Sequential file is detailed",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "The Use of electronic systems to send an unsolicited e-mail to someone's address is known as ______",
A: "Hacking",
B: "Spamming",
C: "Internet fraud",
D: "Piracy",
answer: "A. Hacking",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "Which of the following ideals is protected by copyright?",
A: "Ideas",
B: "Profit",
C: "Expression of ideas",
D: "Inexperience",
answer: "C. Expression of ideas",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]